<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ron Kitainik: Blog &amp; Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ron Kitainik: Blog &amp; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Orbit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/orbit/</guid>
      <description>As a member of UBC Orbit&amp;rsquo;s OBC (On-Board Computer) subteam, I&amp;rsquo;ve made various contributions and improvements to our satellite&amp;rsquo;s electronics.&#xA;Above is a custom FFC (Flat Flexible Cable) I designed to interface between the OBC (On-Board Computer) and COMMS subsystems.&#xA;I had to take a number of factors into consideration for this design:&#xA;The COMMS board processes and amplifies received RF signals, so I had to design this board with high frequency signals of about 1-2A in mind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulated Self-Driving Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph353/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph353/</guid>
      <description>A virtual robot that detects targets and bypasses obstacles to compete in a race.&#xA;Programmed in OpenCV and simulated in Gazebo.&#xA;I have implemented line following from a video feed using HSV thresholding, and imported it into ROS Gazebo to allow the robot to follow any terrain file.&#xA;Your browser does not support the video tag. Currently WIP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:31:02 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Ron, a 3rd year Eng Phys student at UBC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5: Hiatus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:36:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog5/</guid>
      <description>Weekly updates have turned out to be difficult as well as unnecessary. Events seem to come in clusters; to paraphrase Lenin (without endorsement), there are months where nothing happens, and there are weeks where months happen. This month was the former: mostly midterms, although with one exception.&#xA;Halloweek The last week of October was extraordinarily busy, lots of gigantic assignments and little time to finish them all. I ended up missing one, but did it the following day for practice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4: Many Events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:30:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog4/</guid>
      <description>I had two midterms and three events this week. I am becoming a true fizzer.&#xA;Thursday In the morning I had my class 5 exam which I had booked months before. I got barely any sleep overnight but somehow passed by 1 point!&#xA;I then drove to school to catch a mech lecture and my group&amp;rsquo;s lab, where we assembled some hydraulic circuits. I was convinced by the hydro prefix that the fluid would be water, but to my amusement and horror it was oil, and it went everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3: Joining Orbit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 10:59:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog3/</guid>
      <description>Updates Last week I joined UBC Orbit, a design team that is working on ALEASAT, a satellite equipped with radio and camera capabilities that can take and send pictures of any* location on earth.&#xA;*excluding military bases, nuclear silos, alien colonies, etc.&#xA;I am making PCBs (printed circuit boards) for the OBC (on board computer). OBC is a very small subteam, and I am the most junior among them, but that just means I get to learn the most.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2: Starting Third Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 22:36:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog2/</guid>
      <description>I am now a 3rd year student. For anybody else this would indicate the halfway point of their university experience, but in my program I&amp;rsquo;ll be lucky if it&amp;rsquo;s one third.&#xA;Still, time flies. It feels like just yesterday I was building cardboard chairs and claws, and just a day before that I was folding origami in my high school science class. But this makes sense: due to logarithmic time perception it feels like we&amp;rsquo;ve lived half our life by age 21.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1: Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 23:15:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Here is the first real content of my blog. This inaugural post will (briefly) document the assembly of my team&amp;rsquo;s robots for the ENPH253 course.&#xA;Our challenge this year was unlike any previous one: we had to build not one, but two fully autonomous robots that could cook, assemble, and serve 3d printed food. There were a variety of recipes, ranging from simple salads to deluxe cheeseburgers.&#xA;Fig. 1. The competition surface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0. Hello</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 22:38:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hello Welcome to my blog. Here is my first post, at least the first that made it out of local testing and into deployment.&#xA;I will update this blog biweekly with chronicles of my escapades as well as those less exciting things called projects.&#xA;Thanks to Steven Chen for inspiring me to start this and helping set it up.&#xA;My other stuff can be found on my github or gitlab. I prefer the latter as it isn&amp;rsquo;t microsoft affiliated, but it is trickier to use, as it couldn&amp;rsquo;t deploy this site no matter what I tried.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Cooking Robots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph253/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/enph253/</guid>
      <description>In summer of 2024 I collaborated with three other students to build a pair of fully automatic robots that served food in a kitchen-like course.&#xA;The environment included various signals and surfaces for our robots to follow.&#xA;I developed PCBs for the robot including a phototransistor reflectance sensor, a two-motor H-bridge, and a hardware signal debouncer, shown below.&#xA;I routed the schematic and developed this small, stylized board.&#xA;(The theme is because our team name was the Krusty Krab)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/origami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/origami/</guid>
      <description>When I&amp;rsquo;m not learning or exercising I am doing origami. Here are some of my best models.&#xA;Above is a Tree Frog by Satoshi Kamiya&#xA;Harpy Eagle by Jang Yong Ik</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
