<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ron Kitainik: Blog &amp; Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ron Kitainik: Blog &amp; Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 23:53:46 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ron-kit.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6: New Year</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 23:53:46 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time passes quickly. Macroscopically, we are somehow already a quarter of the way through the century; microscopically, it has been nearly 2 months since my last biweekly blog. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my defense, not many weeks are as eventful as the one I wrote about previously. The majority of my waking hours are dedicated to locking in. Thus I have delayed further authorship until a well justified cause arose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-of-term&#34;&gt;End of term&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finals were brutal and merciless. The most difficult classes I took this term (and probably ever) were applied PDEs, quantum phys, and mech design, and as luck would have it all three of their finals were placed in 2 consecutive days. I could have done well in each of these classes individually with prep time, but the clustering definitely led to a measurable decrease in my performance in all three. I suppose I was just dealt a bad hand, maybe as punishment for my hubris in taking mthe math class a year early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FFC for UBC Orbit</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/orbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/orbit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a member of UBC Orbit&amp;rsquo;s OBC (On-Board Computer) subteam, I&amp;rsquo;ve made various contributions and improvements to our satellite&amp;rsquo;s electronics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;ffc.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Above is a custom FFC (Flat Flexible Cable) I designed to interface between the OBC (On-Board Computer) and COMMS subsystems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had to take a number of factors into consideration for this design:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The COMMS board processes and amplifies received RF signals, so I had to design this board with high frequency signals of about 1-2A in mind.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also, conditions in space, even in low orbit, are much more hostile than those on Earth, so the materials were also chosen carefully.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instead of the polyester that most COTS cables are made of, I used a polyimide coverlay to minimize degassing, and a gold surface finish for longevity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;layerstack.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulated Self-Driving Robot</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/enph353/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/enph353/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A virtual robot that detects features and navigates terrain to compete in a race. Programmed with OpenCV, connected with ROS, and simulated in Gazebo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;competition-map&#34;&gt;Competition Map&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;353map.gif&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-log&#34;&gt;Development Log&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started with a very basic prebuilt robot, not much more than a box on wheels, and developed a system to detect the road.&#xA;The standard approach to this is to apply a Gaussian blur followed by a binary threshold, but I opted for HSV thresholding instead (seen in the cover image), which procured a very strong boundary between road and ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 19:31:02 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Ron, a 3rd year engineering physics student at UBC. I like energy, space, and robotics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My grandest ambitions are accessible space travel and universal nuclear power, while my more down-to-earth interests include biking, music, and origami.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting my website. Feel free to check out my writing and projects!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;headshot.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;width: 100%; height: 100vh; display: flex; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe class=&#34;pdf&#34; &#xA;        src=&#34;Ron_Kitainik_Resume_2025.pdf&#34; &#xA;        width=&#34;100%&#34; &#xA;        height=&#34;auto&#34; &#xA;        style=&#34;border: none;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5: Hiatus</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:36:14 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Weekly updates have turned out to be difficult as well as unnecessary. Events seem to come in clusters; to paraphrase a well-known quote, there are months where nothing happens, and there are weeks where months happen. This month was the former: mostly midterms, although with one exception.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;halloweek&#34;&gt;Halloweek&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;images/halloween.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last week of October was extraordinarily busy, lots of gigantic assignments and little time to finish them all. I ended up missing one, but did it the following day for practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4: Many Events</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:30:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;images/october.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had two midterms and three events this week, very hectic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;thursday&#34;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the morning I had my class 5 exam which I had booked months before. I got barely any sleep overnight but somehow passed by 1 point!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;images/pass.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I then drove to school to catch a mech lecture and my group&amp;rsquo;s lab, where we assembled some hydraulic circuits. I was convinced by the hydro prefix that the fluid would be water, but to my amusement and horror it was oil, and it went everywhere. Horror because I was dressed up for the job fair and any oil stain on my nice shirt would be generational aura debt. Thankfully I was spared from this embarrassment, and although I did end up getting another stain from food, it was hidden by the generously provided nametags.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3: Joining Orbit</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 10:59:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates&#34;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ubcorbit.com&#34;&gt;UBC Orbit&lt;/a&gt;, a design team that is working on ALEASAT, a satellite equipped with radio and camera capabilities that can take and send pictures of any* location on earth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$ *_\text{excluding military bases, nuclear silos, alien colonies, etc.} $&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am making PCBs (printed circuit boards) for the OBC (on board computer). OBC is a very small subteam, and I am the most junior among them, but that just means I get to learn the most.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2: Starting Third Year</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 22:36:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am now a 3rd year student. For anybody else this would indicate the halfway point of their university experience, but in my program I&amp;rsquo;ll be lucky if it&amp;rsquo;s one third.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Still, time flies. It feels like just yesterday I was building cardboard chairs and claws, and just a day before that I was folding origami in my high school science class. But this makes sense: due to logarithmic time perception it feels like we&amp;rsquo;ve lived &lt;a href=&#34;https://suryad.com/blog/percieved-age&#34;&gt;half our life by age 21&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1: Robot</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 23:15:10 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the first real content of my blog. This inaugural post will (briefly) document the assembly of my team&amp;rsquo;s robots for the ENPH253 course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our challenge this year was unlike any previous one: we had to build not one, but two fully autonomous robots that could cook, assemble, and serve 3d printed food. There were a variety of recipes, ranging from simple salads to deluxe cheeseburgers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;images/surface.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fig. 1. The competition surface.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0. Hello</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 22:38:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog. Here is my first post, at least the first that made it out of  testing and to deployment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will update this blog &lt;del&gt;biweekly&lt;/del&gt; occasionally  with stories from my life and write about my work on projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://shengwen.me/&#34;&gt;Steven Chen&lt;/a&gt; for inspiring me to start this and helping set it up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My other stuff can be found on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ron-kit/&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ron-kit/&#34;&gt;gitlab&lt;/a&gt;. I prefer the latter as it isn&amp;rsquo;t microsoft affiliated, but it is trickier to use, as it couldn&amp;rsquo;t deploy this site no matter what I tried. Eventually I&amp;rsquo;d like to move there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Cooking Robots</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/enph253/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/enph253/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In summer of 2024 I collaborated with three other students to build a pair of fully automatic robots that served food in a kitchen-like course.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;kitchen.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The environment included various signals and surfaces for our robots to follow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I developed PCBs for the robot including a phototransistor reflectance sensor, a two-motor H-bridge, and a hardware signal debouncer, shown below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;schematic.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I routed the schematic and developed this small, stylized board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origami</title>
      <link>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/origami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ron-kit.github.io/projects/origami/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m not learning or exercising I am doing origami. Here are some of my best models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Above is a Tree Frog by Satoshi Kamiya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;eagle.jpeg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harpy Eagle by Jang Yong Ik&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
